

WEB DEVELOPER · ENGINEER

Quezon City, Metro Manila, Philippines

□ (+63) 9212324170 | ■ marvin.baltazar@gmail.com | ★ marvs.me | • marvs

"If you do what is easy your life will be hard."

Summary

Marvin, known as Marvs to his friends, is a full-stack web developer with 8 years of expertise using the Ruby on Rails framework and more than 11 years of software development experience. He also has deep knowledge about server setup and architecture and maintains a private server for hobbies and personal websites. He also has Project Management experience and has been involved in teams using either Agile or traditional (Waterfall) methodologies.

Education

University of the Philippines (Diliman)

Quezon City, Philippines

June 2000 - March 2005

B.S. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

- Webmaster of the Communications Engineering Laboratory
- · Member of the Engineering Radio Guild

Skills

Ruby on Rails/Ruby, Project Management, Data Modeling, Javascript/jQuery, HTML/Haml/Erb, CSS/SCSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, JSON, XML, SOAP Integrations, RSpec, Cucumber, Automation (Capistrano, Chef), Continuous Integration (TravisCI, CircleCI), Agile (Scrum), Git, Gitolite, Linux (Ubuntu, Mint, CentOS, Gentoo), Nginx, VPS

Experience

LaunchPad Recruits Quezon City, Philippines

PH DEVELOPMENT LEAD

August 2012 - Present

- · LaunchPad Recruits is a video led HR system for candidate screening, hiring and assessment that help employers acquire talented employees
- As the first application developer, helped build the company from the ground up
- Developed a significant portion of the application code using the Ruby on Rails framework
- · Designed and developed a REST API that enabled the company to integrate with several prominent Applicant Tracking Systems
- Developed custom API integrations for large companies using JSON, XML, SOAP, Oauth2
- · Designed and developed the API that integrates the web app to the iOS and Android mobile app
- · Performed server maintenance, troubleshooting, and security, making sure that the application is PCI compliant and passes penetration testing
- Manages task allocation and project scheduling for the PH development team and provides guidance and support for other team members
- Manages releases, feature branches, and deploys in the application

Freelance Quezon City, Philippines

RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER

January 2012 - July 2012

• Developed a web application for a document management system using Ruby on Rails. This involved both back-end components, interfacing with an external Java library, and front-end features using Javascript

SourcePad International, Inc.

Pasig City, Philippines

RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER

June 2011 - January 2012

- · SourcePad is a NY based internet consulting company with a focus on developing web and mobile applications for startups
- Developed web applications for US and EU projects using Ruby on Rails

ASTRA (Philippines), Inc.

Quezon City, Philippines

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2008 - January 2011

- ASTRA is a Product Research and Development company that produces its own suite of products as well as doing custom software development for clients both local and abroad
- Developed web applications for local and foreign projects using Ruby on Rails
- Provided technical support for clients and performed server setup and maintenance
- Developed a pluggable CMS product using Rails engines
- Managed a team of developers for a university management system web application
- Part of a team that designed and developed a Human Resource System web application
- Provided training and guidance to other engineers through meetings and code reviews

Canon Information Technologies (Philippines) Inc.

Quezon City, PH & Tokyo, Japan

HARDWARE ENGINEER May 2005 - March 2008

- CITECH is a subsidiary of Canon Inc. and serves as a Reasearch and Development company that provides designs for application-specific ICs and verification of Canon's image-processing modules
- Performs design verification of hardware modules used in Canon's multi-function printers
- Created test plans, documentation and created the code for utilities, models, and monitors for verification using System C and e languages
- Provided training and guidance to other engineers through face-to-face lectures, meetings, code and document reviews, and created training
 materials
- Researched and created patent applications for the company

UP Communications Engineering Laboratory

Quezon City, Philippines

WEBMASTER/STUDENT AFFILIATE

May 2003 - April 2005

- The Communications Engineering Laboratory is a research and instructional facility engaged in the design, integration, analysis, and testing of wireless communication devices, circuits, and systems
- Developed and maintained the website of the Communications Engineering Laboratory
- · Archived previous research materials and published them on the web

Other Projects

http://marvs.me

PERSONAL WEBSITE

• Profile website/portfolio built using Ruby on Rails, with links to other accounts

https://techandfi.com

PERSONAL BLOG

· Articles about software programming, backend, server setup, as well as thoughts regarding personal finance and financial independence

https://rubygems.org/gems/psei

PSEI RUBY GEM

• PSEI is a Ruby gem that returns the end-of-day trading values in the Philippine Stock Exchange

https://rubygems.org/gems/navfund

NAVFUND RUBY GEM

 Navfund is a Ruby gem that fetches (via scraping) the values of the current NAVPU/NAVPS of several UITFs/Mutual Funds. Currently it only supports Philippine providers

Extras.

Electronics Engineer License

LICENSE NO. 0035973November 2005

• Passed the Electronics and Communications Engineering licensure exams

JLPT Level 4/N5

JAPANESE LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY TEST

Passed the Japanese Language Proficiency Test for basic Japanese